Let go of my hand this instant, sinner!
I would rather die than be saved by you!
I will not bear the disgrace of it!
Hey! Stop!
Don't, you idiot!
What's suicide gonna do?
Nothing, that's what!
So suck it up, act like a
knight, and quit being an idiot!
Idiot how dare you a
common criminal insult me i
demand an apology oh shut
up i called you an idiot!
Because you're acting
like an idiot idiot listen
if i let go when you die
then what eugio's still
in the cathedral and
he's on his way up to the
pontifex and it's your
job to stop him you idiot
instead of checking
out an integrity knight
should be thinking how to
get back in But not you!
You're so dumb you forgot your priorities,
and that's why you're an idiot!
Look here.
I won't allow a rogue like
you to insult me any further.
That said, your words have
a certain logic to them.
However, death is more tolerable
than being saved out of pity,
and letting me fall
would benefit your cause.
So why don't you explain why
I must accept this situation?
I'll try.
Thank
you!
HAAAAAAA!
Eugeo and me,
we didn't break in and get this far up the
cathedral just to
destroy the Axiom Church.
We know the Dark Territory is
gonna invade the Human Empire,
and we want to protect it same as you.
You're one of the most powerful
integrity knights around and if I let you
die we lose a valuable ally we can't
afford that why should I believe you you
violated the greatest taboo of all
spilling the blood of a fellow human and
cutting them down that's true but the
axiom church and the
taboo index are wrong.
Eugeo and I had a good reason
to attack Raios and Umber.
The law slid upper class nobles like
them to whatever they want to innocent?
people.
Those bastards were gonna rape Ronie
and Tiese and get away with it.
Do you think that's right?
Do you think that's
fair?
Well, is it?
Answer me!
Is it right?
The law is the law.
A crime is a crime.
If the people are allowed to decide what
is right and wrong
according to their needs,
how will we maintain order in the land?
Yeah, well, Administrator
came up with all the laws.
So who decides if she's right or wrong?
Sure, God!
If I'm such a sinner,
then how come I haven't been fried
by a bolt of lightning by now?
Simple.
It is the will of Stacia, and
we knights enforce her will.
We are her divine servants.
All you knights in force are lies, and
me and Eugeo came here to prove it.
If we defeat Administrator,
we'll enter tyranny.
We're not the bad guys.
If we were, I'd have let you fall.
It's coming loose!
Stick your sword in the wall, or we die!
What are you waiting for?
Do it!
Mine's about to come out! Hurry!
I did not save you, sinner.
I returned the favor is all.
Besides, our duel has yet to be decided.
If we survive.
Oh well, at least we're even now.
I got an idea if you want to hear.
We can't hang here all day.
Our arms will get tired, but if we work
together we can find a way back in.
So like, what do you say
we call a truce till then?
A truce? Yeah.
We can't break the wall
so we'll have to climb.
It'll be easier if we help each other.
You say help each other.
How do you propose we do that?
If one of us starts to fall, the
other stops them, that's all.
If we had a rope, we could
use it as a safety line.
I didn't bring one, though.
I hate to admit it, but
that does sound logical.
Very well.
However, the moment we set foot
inside again, I will cut you down.
True, sir, no.
Do not forget that.
I'll try not to.
Now then.
You said we needed rope.
System call.
Form object.
Change shape.
W-was that the matter conversion art?
Did you not hear what I said?
I changed the shape of an object.
Only the pontifex can use the formal
arts to change an object's properties,
you dolt.
Sorry, ma 'am.
Hey, um, I just thought of something else.
What is it?
It's about that dragon of yours.
Can't you, like, summon it to come get us?
Mine cannot fly further than the
landing platforms on the 30th floor.
No dragon can.
Even my uncle... Pardon.
Even the commander's is not allowed.
The upper floors are off-limits.
Even the birds stay away.
The Pontifex herself made it so.
She cast a formal art, one so
advanced I do not even know it.
Oh well.
I guess that leaves us
with three options then.
Go up or down, or bust
through the wall again.
The third option is out.
The cathedral walls are endowed
with nearly infinite life.
And, as you saw, they
regenerate quickly. Perfect.
Alright, I'm thinking we should climb.
Do you know if there's anywhere
up top where we can get in?
There is.
The Morningstar lookout
is on the 95th floor.
There are no walls, just pillars.
If we can climb up that far,
we can easily get back in.
That said,
if we manage to survive the climb and get
in, our truce is off, and I will slay you.
I know, I didn't forget about our deal.
So are you okay with climbing up or what?
Yes.
Going up is more practical than down, but
how do you plan on scaling a sheer wall?
It won't be easy.
System call!
Generate metallic element! Wedge shape!
Is that safe to stand on?
Seems to be, for now.
System call.
Generate metallic element.
You know, I think this will work.
Well, don't just hang there.
Do what I did.
I cannot.
Huh?
What do you mean?
I said, I cannot.
Yeah, I heard that.
But what do you mean you can't?
If I can make a wedge, you can.
And you're so strong,
you shouldn't have any problem
hoisting - That is not what I meant!
I have never been in a situation
like this before today.
At the risk of sounding weak, it is
all I can manage to just hang on.
I cannot climb up onto
such a slender step.
No worries.
How about if I pull you up to the bar?
Would that work for you instead?
I would appreciate it.
Okay, first I'm going
to take up the slack.
here goes
I'm
ready go
on and pull your sword out
Grab the wall to balance.
All right, I'm going to
climb up a little higher now.
I'll let you know when I'm ready.
Please be careful. Always.
Hey, Asuna. Huh?
How's your fish?
I bet they caught it right
off the side of the turtle.
Yeah, maybe they did.
Or maybe they brought it. Who?
Hmm.
I doubt it.
Doesn't look like a fishing boat.
It's got way too many antennas.
Is it a battleship?
No, it's Japanese.
We don't have battleships
in service anymore.
Ms.
Yuki, Dr. Kojiro, morning.
Good morning.
Good morning, Mr. Nakanishi.
If that's not a warship, is it SDF?
MSDF.
And Escort Ship is the
official designation.
The one out there is the DD-119 Asahi.
She's a five-ton general purpose vessel.
She's one of two escort ships in service.
Her sister's ship is the Shiranui.
Hey, um, it looks like
it's moving away now.
They are the second
generation of her class.
Pardon me.
Lieutenant Colonel Kikuoka, I just saw
the Asahi changing course to the west.
Wasn't she supposed to stay with
us until 1200, day after tomorrow?
Yes, sir. Right away.
Excuse me, ladies.
Something's come up.
It must be something important.
Yeah...
System call.
Generate Metallic Element.
The light.
Generating containers uses up a
significant amount of sacred power.
And once Solace sets, we'll be lucky
if we can create one bar an hour.
How high up do you think we are now?
Um, I think we're already
past the 85th floor.
The 95th floor is still
quite a long way off.
Yeah, and climbing's gonna be even more
dangerous once it's too dark to see.
Hey, check it out!
There's something on that ledge!
They look like statues
from here, which is odd.
No one below can see them.
Oh, well, they're lost.
But maybe we can rest on them.
They look like they're about six meter...
six miles away.
We're gonna need two more bars.
You only need two, Yusei?
Very well, then.
I was saving it for an emergency.
It appears this would be one.
Form object.
Wedge shape.
Here, use these.
Thanks.
I owe ya.
Get ready.
I'm pulling you up.
Right.
You good?
I'm fine.
No.
Oh, my God.
That sure is one ugly statue.
It's from the Dark Territory!
Alice!
Draw your sword! Hurry!
There's two more coming!
Atlas!
We're screwed if they attack at once.
What the hell's up with her?
Alice!
Hang on as tight as you can!
No, just a moment.
I'll apologize later if we survive.
Get ready!
One, two, three!
What were you thinking, you idiot?
Have you lost your mind?
I didn't have any other choice.
I had to act.
We'll talk later.
Here they come!
There is no doubt.
But why are they here?
I was wondering when you'd snap out of it.
Do you know what these monsters are?
Yes, I do indeed.
Indeed, they are familiars
from the Dark Territory,
conjured from lumps of corrupt soil by
sorcerers who practice the dark arts.
Such disgusting things.
We call these creatures
minions. That figures.
But why are they here?
This is the holiest place in the land
and they're just hanging out on it.
I'd like to know why as well.
They should not be here fouling the
very symbol of all that is good.
I cannot believe they escaped the
notice of the integrity knights
to roost on the central cathedral
where even the birds cannot land.
It's unreal!
Yeah, well not if administrator
wanted these suckers here.
I don't know why she
would but it's possible
At this point it wouldn't surprise me.
Watch it!
The other two are coming around again.
I know this is not my first time in battle
Do you need assistance with that one?
Nope, I can handle him.
you okay i am i was just
thinking how strange your moves
are If you performed them
at the Midsummer Festival,
you would attract quite an audience.
Thanks for the compliment.
Hang on.
Have you been to the
Midsummer Festival before?
I thought it was only for commoners.
Even kids from the upper-class
family stayed away,
at least the ones I was
going to the academy with.
Do not mention me in the same
breath as those so-called nobles.
I've seen it. I...
I've been.
Alice?
No.
I have only heard of it.
One of the priests must
have told me of it.
We Integrity Knights,
we are prohibited from mingling with the
townsfolk except in the line of duty.
What?
Minion blood carries disease.
You should wipe it off.
Huh? Oh.
No! Not like that!
Honestly, could a man
be any more thoughtless?
Are you so uncouth you do
not even have a handkerchief?
N-no, I don't.
As I thought.
Use mine.
Thanks.
I appreciate it.
I would like it washed and
returned before I slay you.
Now that I think of it, ever
since I met Kirito two years ago,
he's always been with me.
I've forgotten what it's like to be alone.
I hope he's okay.
Knowing him, I'm sure he is.
He's probably climbing the
tower, looking for a way in.
Along with Alice.
The 90th Floor.
An Integrity Knight is in there.
Here goes.
It's a giant bath.
Easy, kid.
I need to stretch before we start.
I just got back from
patrolling the borderlands.
Riding that dragon nonstop
sure does a number on the body.
Haha.
everything turns to dust to
Forgive me no more.
And everything turns to dust to dust
Next time, the legendary hero.